[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Who was the first man created by God?",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Seth",
      "Noah"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 2:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What did God create on the first day?",
    "answer": "Light",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Water",
      "Earth"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 1:3"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Who built an ark to survive the flood?",
    "answer": "Noah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jonah",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 6:14"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What was the name of Abraham’s son?",
    "answer": "Isaac",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Ishmael",
      "Jacob"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 21:3"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What sign did God give after the flood?",
    "answer": "Rainbow",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Olive branch",
      "Dove"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 9:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Who interpreted Pharaoh’s dreams about the famine?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Benjamin",
      "Judah"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 41:15-16"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What sea did Moses and the Israelites cross?",
    "answer": "Red Sea",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jordan River",
      "Sea of Galilee"
    ],
    "reference": "Exodus 14:21"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Who led the Israelites into the Promised Land?",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Caleb",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": "Joshua 1:1-2"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What food did God provide in the desert?",
    "answer": "Manna",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Quail",
      "Water from the rock"
    ],
    "reference": "Exodus 16:15"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Who was the high priest when Samuel was a boy?",
    "answer": "Eli",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Samuel",
      "Phinehas"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Samuel 1:9"
  },
  {
    "id": 505,
    "question": "According to the Beatitudes who will be filled?",
    "answer": "Those who hunger and thirst for righteousness",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The wicked at the judgement",
      "The merciful"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 511,
    "question": "After Jesus was arrested, which disciple disowned him three times?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Thomas"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 513,
    "question": "Who was thrown into a pit by his brothers?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Benjamin",
      "Judah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 518,
    "question": "Benjamin was the youngest son of which person from the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Esau",
      "Joseph"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 521,
    "question": "Complete the following: \"The light of the body is…\"",
    "answer": "The eye",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The heart",
      "The mind"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 6:22"
  },
  {
    "id": 524,
    "question": "Complete this verse: \"How beautiful upon the mountains are the feet of him that bringeth…\"",
    "answer": "good tidings",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "good news",
      "peace"
    ],
    "reference": "Isaiah 52:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 527,
    "question": "Even though Abram and Sarah were too old what did God promise them?",
    "answer": "A son",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A daughter",
      "Land"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 528,
    "question": "Finish this Proverb: \"Labour not to be...\"",
    "answer": "rich",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "vain",
      "righteous"
    ],
    "reference": "Proverbs 23:4"
  },
  {
    "id": 529,
    "question": "Finish this proverb: \"Where there is no vision...\"",
    "answer": "the people perish",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "the land will perish",
      "light is lost"
    ],
    "reference": "Proverbs 29:18"
  },
  {
    "id": 531,
    "question": "How long did the flood rain fall?",
    "answer": "40 days / 40 nights",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "30 days / 30 nights",
      "50 days / 50 nights"
    ],
    "reference": "Gen 7:12"
  },
  {
    "id": 532,
    "question": "For how long did Jesus stay with his disciples after his resurrection?",
    "answer": "40 days",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "30 days",
      "50 days"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 533,
    "question": "For which type of tree was Lebanon well known?",
    "answer": "Cedar",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Olive",
      "Cypress"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 538,
    "question": "How did God appear to Moses in the wilderness?",
    "answer": "A burning bush",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "In the tabernacle",
      "In the water"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 542,
    "question": "How did Judas end up revealing Jesus’s identity to the Roman officials?",
    "answer": "With a kiss",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "With a hug",
      "With a handshake"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 544,
    "question": "How did Moses throw into bitter water to turn it sweet?",
    "answer": "Wood",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Salt",
      "Rock"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 546,
    "question": "How did Stephen, one of the deacons in the New Testament, die?",
    "answer": "Stoned to death",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hung on a cross",
      "Drowned at sea"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 553,
    "question": "How long did the flood cover the earth?",
    "answer": "150 days",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "140 days",
      "160 days"
    ],
    "reference": "Gen 7:24"
  },
  {
    "id": 554,
    "question": "What time was it when Jesus was crucified?",
    "answer": "9am",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "8am",
      "10am"
    ],
    "reference": "Mark 15:25"
  },
  {
    "id": 555,
    "question": "How long was the ark?",
    "answer": "300 cubits",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "270 cubits",
      "330 cubits"
    ],
    "reference": "Gen 6:15"
  },
  {
    "id": 556,
    "question": "How many years were the children of Israel in Babylonian captivity?",
    "answer": "70",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "60",
      "80"
    ],
    "reference": "Jer 25:11"
  },
  {
    "id": 558,
    "question": "How many books are in the Bible?",
    "answer": "66",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "56",
      "76"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 559,
    "question": "How many books are in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "27",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "22",
      "32"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 560,
    "question": "How many books are in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "39",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "29",
      "49"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 568,
    "question": "How many days and nights did Jesus fast in the desert?",
    "answer": "40 days & 40 nights",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "30 days and 30 nights",
      "50 days and 50 nights"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 569,
    "question": "How many days did God take to create the world?",
    "answer": "6",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "5",
      "4"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 574,
    "question": "How many people boarded Noah’s Ark?",
    "answer": "8",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "7",
      "9"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 577,
    "question": "How many plagues were in Egypt?",
    "answer": "10",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "9",
      "12"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 578,
    "question": "How many sons did Abraham have?",
    "answer": "8",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "7",
      "9"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 579,
    "question": "How many wise men visited the baby Jesus?",
    "answer": "We don't know",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "5",
      "2"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 581,
    "question": "How many years of famine did Joseph prophecy to Pharaoh?",
    "answer": "7",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "14",
      "12"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 584,
    "question": "How old was Jesus when he began his public ministry?",
    "answer": "30",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "29",
      "33"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 3:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 585,
    "question": "How old was Jesus when he tarried behind in Jerusalem after attending the Passover feast with Mary and Joseph?",
    "answer": "12",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "8",
      "13"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 2:41-43"
  },
  {
    "id": 587,
    "question": "How old was Moses when he gave God’s message to Pharaoh: “Let my people go”?",
    "answer": "80",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "40",
      "120"
    ],
    "reference": "Exod 7:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 588,
    "question": "How were sins forgiven in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Animal sacrifice",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Human sacrifice",
      "Offering the first fruits"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 595,
    "question": "In what city did Mary, Martha, and Lazarus live?",
    "answer": "Bethany",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Nazareth"
    ],
    "reference": "John 11:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 596,
    "question": "In what city was Jesus born?",
    "answer": "Bethlehem",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nazareth",
      "Jerusalem"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 597,
    "question": "In what language was most of the New Testament given?",
    "answer": "Greek",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hebrew",
      "Aramaic"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 598,
    "question": "In what language was most of the Old Testament given?",
    "answer": "Hebrew",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Greek",
      "Aramaic"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 599,
    "question": "In what water was Jesus baptized?",
    "answer": "River Jordan",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Red Sea",
      "Sea of Galilee"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 602,
    "question": "In which New Testament Book does Jesus say \"\"I and my Father are one\"\"?",
    "answer": "Book of John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Book of Luke",
      "Book of Matthew"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 603,
    "question": "Horeb is the name of a what?",
    "answer": "A mountain",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A river",
      "A desert"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 607,
    "question": "Jesus was born in Bethlehem of Judea in the days of what king?",
    "answer": "Herod",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Pharoah",
      "Nero"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 2:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 610,
    "question": "Many of the New Testament's letters to churches were written by who?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Barnabas",
      "Peter"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 611,
    "question": "What profession was Matthew in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Tax collector",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Fisherman",
      "Physician"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 615,
    "question": "What does El Shaddai mean?",
    "answer": "Almighty God",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Prince of peace",
      "Ruler"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 619,
    "question": "People who pray just to be seen of men are called what?",
    "answer": "Hypocrites",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Pharisees",
      "Sinners"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 6:5"
  },
  {
    "id": 622,
    "question": "What was Jesus doing in the boat when it was in danger of sinking?",
    "answer": "Sleeping",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Praying",
      "Singing"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 8:24"
  },
  {
    "id": 626,
    "question": "What nation was Goliath from?",
    "answer": "Philistines",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Amalekites",
      "Moabites"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 628,
    "question": "What are Paul's letters called?",
    "answer": "The Epistles",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The Gospels",
      "The Books of Wisdom"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 629,
    "question": "What are the first five books of the Old Testament referred to?",
    "answer": "Pentateuch",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Tanakh",
      "Prophecies"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 632,
    "question": "Who was the first man to be taken into heaven?",
    "answer": "Enoch",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Elijah",
      "Elisha"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 633,
    "question": "What day did God create man?",
    "answer": "6",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "5",
      "7"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 638,
    "question": "What did God divide when He created Earth?",
    "answer": "Light from darkness",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Earth from water",
      "Plains from mountains"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 640,
    "question": "What did God use the rib of Adam to do?",
    "answer": "Create Eve",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Create land",
      "Create the serpent"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 645,
    "question": "What did Jesus say would happen to the temple buildings?",
    "answer": "Be demolished",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Be cleansed",
      "Be renewed"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 21:6"
  },
  {
    "id": 646,
    "question": "What did Joseph's brothers do after they put him in the pit?",
    "answer": "Sold him as a slave",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Gave him a meal",
      "Sent him home"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 649,
    "question": "What did Moses receive on Mount Sinai?",
    "answer": "The 10 commandments",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Manna",
      "The ark of the covenant"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 651,
    "question": "What did Solomon ask God to give him?",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Power",
      "Riches"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 652,
    "question": "What did the Israelites worship when Moses met God on Mount Sinai?",
    "answer": "A Golden Calf",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The sun",
      "Pharoah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 653,
    "question": "What did the serpent tempt Eve to do in the Garden of Eden?",
    "answer": "Eat fruit from the tree",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Curse God",
      "Betray Adam"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 654,
    "question": "What does David bring to Jerusalem to bless the religious city?",
    "answer": "The Ark of the Covenant",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The bronze serpent",
      "The tabernacle"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 657,
    "question": "What does Paul say is the fulfillment of the law?",
    "answer": "Love",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Faith",
      "Hope"
    ],
    "reference": "Rom 13:10"
  },
  {
    "id": 659,
    "question": "What does Simon Peter do for a living before he becomes an apostle?",
    "answer": "Fisherman",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Tax collector",
      "Carpenter"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 660,
    "question": "What does Solomon say about sin?",
    "answer": "That no one does not sin",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "That it will continue forever",
      "That we can overcome it"
    ],
    "reference": "Ecclesiastes 7:20"
  },
  {
    "id": 661,
    "question": "What does the word gospel mean?",
    "answer": "Good news",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Good works",
      "God's law"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 663,
    "question": "What happened when Jesus died?",
    "answer": "An earthquake",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A volcanic eruption",
      "A hailstorm"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 27:51"
  },
  {
    "id": 665,
    "question": "Who was the first man who was murdered?",
    "answer": "Abel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Seth",
      "Cain"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 666,
    "question": "Who led the Israelites around Jericho?",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Caleb",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 669,
    "question": "What is the common name given to the first four books of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "The Gospels",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The Epistles",
      "The Law"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 670,
    "question": "What is the first book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Genesis",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Exodus",
      "Deuteronomy"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 671,
    "question": "What is the first of the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "You shall have no other gods before me",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "You shalt not murder",
      "You shall steal"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 672,
    "question": "What is the Holy Trinity?",
    "answer": "Father, Son, and Holy Spirit",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sun, moon, and stars",
      "Joseph, Mary, and Jesus"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 673,
    "question": "What is the last book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Malachi",
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 674,
    "question": "What is the last book in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Malachi",
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 675,
    "question": "What is the longest book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Psalms",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 685,
    "question": "What is the second commandment out of the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "Don't make idols",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Don't steal",
      "Don't murder"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 686,
    "question": "What is the shortest book in the Bible?",
    "answer": "3 John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "2 John",
      "Jude"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 690,
    "question": "What is the third commandment out of the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "Don't take the Lord's name in vain",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Don't steal",
      "Don't murder"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 694,
    "question": "What miracle did Jesus perform at the marriage in Cana?",
    "answer": "Turning water into wine",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Raising the dead",
      "Healing the sick"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 703,
    "question": "What type of insect did John the Baptist eat in the desert?",
    "answer": "Locusts",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Ants",
      "Beatles"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 706,
    "question": "Who was Abraham’s third wife?",
    "answer": "Keturah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hagar",
      "Sarah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 707,
    "question": "What was Abram’s name changed to?",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Michael",
      "Gabriel"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 710,
    "question": "What was God's promise to never send a flood connected to?",
    "answer": "A Rainbow",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A dove",
      "A raven"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 712,
    "question": "What was Hannah’s promise to God?",
    "answer": "To dedicate her son Samuel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "To never leave the temple",
      "To never remarry"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 713,
    "question": "Who was Abram's father?",
    "answer": "Terah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nahor",
      "Haran"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 715,
    "question": "Who was Jacob’s brother?",
    "answer": "Esau",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jacob",
      "Ishmael"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 716,
    "question": "What was Jacob’s eldest son called?",
    "answer": "Rueben",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Judah",
      "Simeon"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 717,
    "question": "What was Jacob’s youngest son called?",
    "answer": "Benjamin",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Joseph",
      "Reuben"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 726,
    "question": "What was Ruth’s husband called?",
    "answer": "Boas",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 728,
    "question": "What was Sarai’s name changed to?",
    "answer": "Sarah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Rachel",
      "Rebekah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 735,
    "question": "What was the first of the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "Don't have any other gods",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Don't steal",
      "Don't murder"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 736,
    "question": "What was the first of the ten plagues in Egypt?",
    "answer": "Water turned into blood",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Death of the firstboard",
      "Locusts"
    ],
    "reference": "Exod 7:20"
  },
  {
    "id": 744,
    "question": "Which angel appeared to Zacharias?",
    "answer": "Gabriel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Michael",
      "Raphael"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 1:19"
  },
  {
    "id": 745,
    "question": "Who was the blind beggar at the gate of Jericho?",
    "answer": "Bartimaeus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Zacchaeus",
      "Lazarus"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 760,
    "question": "What was the second plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Frogs",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Water turned to blood",
      "Darkness"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 761,
    "question": "What Abraham's second son?",
    "answer": "Isaac",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Ishmael",
      "Jacob"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 762,
    "question": "What was the secret behind Samson’s great strength?",
    "answer": "His hair",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "His teeth",
      "His arms"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 767,
    "question": "What was one of Isaac's sons' names?",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Abraham",
      "Judah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 771,
    "question": "What were the two sons of Zebadee (one of the disciples) called?",
    "answer": "James and John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Peter and John",
      "Jacob and Esau"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 772,
    "question": "What’s the final book in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Malachi",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Zechariah",
      "Haggai"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 774,
    "question": "What’s the fourth book of the New Testament?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Luke",
      "Mark"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 785,
    "question": "Where did a jailer find his faith?",
    "answer": "Philippi",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Corinth",
      "Jerusalem"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 786,
    "question": "Where did David work as a shepherd?",
    "answer": "Bethlehem",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nazareth",
      "Jerusalem"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 789,
    "question": "Where did Jesus grow up?",
    "answer": "Nazareth",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Bethlehem",
      "Capernaum"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 790,
    "question": "Where did King Darius order Daniel to be thrown?",
    "answer": "The lion's den",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The colisum",
      "Into the river"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 792,
    "question": "Where did Moses receive the Ten Commandments?",
    "answer": "Mount Sinai",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Mount Horeb",
      "The Red Sea"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 794,
    "question": "Where did Adam and Eve live at the beginning of the world?",
    "answer": "Garden of Eden",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Garden of Gethsemenee",
      "The Garden Tomb"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 798,
    "question": "Where was Jesus taken prisoner?",
    "answer": "Gethsemane",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Golgotha",
      "Nazareth"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 805,
    "question": "Which apostle was crucified upside down?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Thomas"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 806,
    "question": "Which biblical book tells of David and Goliath?",
    "answer": "1 Samuel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "2 Samuel",
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 811,
    "question": "Which book reports on the missionary travels of Paul?",
    "answer": "The Acts of the Apostles",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Galatians",
      "John"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 813,
    "question": "Which commander had leprosy?",
    "answer": "Naaman",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Gehazi",
      "Nabal"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 814,
    "question": "Which disciple found a coin in the mouth of a fish?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Thomas"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 821,
    "question": "Which illness did Mephiboseth suffer from?",
    "answer": "He was lame",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Leprosy",
      "Blindness"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 824,
    "question": "Which king had a sundial?",
    "answer": "Hezekiah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Ahaz",
      "Uzziah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 826,
    "question": "Which New Testament book gives a prophecy on the end of the world?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jude",
      "Acts"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 837,
    "question": "Name a town destroyed by fire and brimstone",
    "answer": "Sodom",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Babylon",
      "Ninevah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 838,
    "question": "Name a bird Noah sent out of the ark",
    "answer": "Raven",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Eagle",
      "Sparrow"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 841,
    "question": "Which type of animal did Balaam ride?",
    "answer": "A donkey",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A camel",
      "A horse"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 843,
    "question": "Who anointed Saul as king?",
    "answer": "Samuel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Eli",
      "David"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 844,
    "question": "Which religious leaders tried to trap Jesus with their questions?",
    "answer": "Pharisees",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Apostles",
      "Levites"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 847,
    "question": "Who asked Pilate for Jesus’ body after the crucifixion?",
    "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nicodemus",
      "Simon of Cyrene"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 848,
    "question": "Who baptizes Jesus?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "Zacharias"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 849,
    "question": "Who begins their book with: \"Hear O heavens and give ear O earth: for the LORD hath spoken…\"",
    "answer": "Isaiah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "1 Chronicles",
      "Leviticus"
    ],
    "reference": "Isaiah 1:2"
  },
  {
    "id": 852,
    "question": "Who commanded the sun and moon to stay still?",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Caleb",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 853,
    "question": "Who did Abraham have his second son with?",
    "answer": "Sarah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Keturah",
      "Hagar"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 855,
    "question": "Who did God call out of Ur to move to Canaan?",
    "answer": "Abram",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Terah",
      "Noah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 856,
    "question": "Who did God tell to build an ark?",
    "answer": "Noah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jonah",
      "Methusaleh"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 858,
    "question": "Who did Jesus teach the Lord's Prayer to?",
    "answer": "His disciples",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Moses",
      "Mary and Joseph"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 861,
    "question": "Who did Samuel anoint as the first King of Israel?",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Solomon"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 863,
    "question": "Who does God call: \"\"my firstborn higher than the kings of the earth\"\"?",
    "answer": "David",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Saul",
      "Adam"
    ],
    "reference": "Psalms 89:27"
  },
  {
    "id": 864,
    "question": "Who had a coat made of camel hair and ate locusts and wild honey?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Elijah",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 866,
    "question": "Who is the stone the builders rejected?",
    "answer": "Jesus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Adam",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 20:9"
  },
  {
    "id": 870,
    "question": "Which apostle denied Jesus?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Thomas"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 874,
    "question": "Who lived in Ur and moved to a country he did not know?",
    "answer": "Abram",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Methusaleh",
      "Jacob"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 875,
    "question": "Who made the bronze snake?",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Aaron",
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 878,
    "question": "Who prophesised the coming of Jesus shortly beforehand?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Zecharius",
      "Simeon"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 879,
    "question": "Who ran to Jesus' empty tomb along with John?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Mary",
      "James"
    ],
    "reference": "John 20:3-4"
  },
  {
    "id": 880,
    "question": "Who recognized Jesus as the Messiah at the Temple as a baby?",
    "answer": "Simeon",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Zacharias"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 885,
    "question": "Who said that the things gained were counted as lost for Christ?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jesus",
      "John"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 886,
    "question": "Who said Do unto others as you would have them to unto you?",
    "answer": "Jesus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Paul",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 7:12"
  },
  {
    "id": 888,
    "question": "Who said to whom: \"\"A person sees what is in front of his eyes but God sees the heart\"\"?",
    "answer": "God to Samuel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "God to David",
      "God to Moses"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 891,
    "question": "Who said: How long will you waver between two opinions?",
    "answer": "Elijah on Mount Carmel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Elisha to the prophets",
      "Joshua to the children of Israel"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 892,
    "question": "Who said: I myself and my house want to serve the Lord!",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Caleb",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 895,
    "question": "Who takes Jesus’s body off the cross?",
    "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nicodemus",
      "Simon of Cyrene"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 897,
    "question": "Who was Abram’s handmaid?",
    "answer": "Hagar",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sarai",
      "Keturah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 898,
    "question": "Who was Abram’s first wife?",
    "answer": "Sarai",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Keturah",
      "Hagar"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 899,
    "question": "Who was assigned to make a sacrifice on behalf of all Israel during Old Testament times?",
    "answer": "The high priest",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The king",
      "The prophet"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 901,
    "question": "Who was Caesar when Jesus was born?",
    "answer": "Augustus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Tiberius",
      "Claudius"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 3:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 902,
    "question": "Who was David’s best friend?",
    "answer": "Jonathan",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Samuel",
      "Saul"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 905,
    "question": "Who was Joseph’s master in Egypt?",
    "answer": "Potiphar",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Pharoah",
      "Moses"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 909,
    "question": "Who was the enemy who took the Ark of the Covenant?",
    "answer": "Philistines",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Amalekites",
      "Moabites"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 911,
    "question": "Who was the father-in-law of Caiaphas?",
    "answer": "Annas",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Zechariah",
      "Herod Antipas"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 915,
    "question": "Who was the first man?",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Seth",
      "Noah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 918,
    "question": "Who was the first son Jacob had with Rachel?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Benjamin",
      "Judah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 919,
    "question": "Who was the first woman?",
    "answer": "Eve",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sarah",
      "Mary"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 924,
    "question": "Who was the king of Judea at the time of Jesus’ birth?",
    "answer": "Herod the Great",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Herod Antipas",
      "Herod Agrippa"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 929,
    "question": "Who was the mother of Moses?",
    "answer": "Jochebed",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Miriam",
      "Zipporah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 933,
    "question": "Who was the Roman ruler when John the Baptist began his ministry?",
    "answer": "Tiberius",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Augustus",
      "Claudius"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 934,
    "question": "Who was the sister of Moses?",
    "answer": "Miriam",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jochebed",
      "Zipporah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 935,
    "question": "Who was the tax collector that climbed up a tree so he could see Jesus?",
    "answer": "Zacchaeus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Bartimaeus",
      "Nicodemus"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 936,
    "question": "Who watched as Moses floated in the basket down the Nile?",
    "answer": "Miriam",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Aaron",
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "reference": "Exodus 2:4"
  },
  {
    "id": 938,
    "question": "Who was Adam & Eve’s first child?",
    "answer": "Cain",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Seth",
      "Abel"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 940,
    "question": "Who were the first apostles called to follow Jesus?",
    "answer": "Peter & Andrew",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "James & John",
      "Judas & Thomas"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 947,
    "question": "Who wrote the Gospel of Mark?",
    "answer": "Mark",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "Paul"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 949,
    "question": "Who was the grandmother of Jacob?",
    "answer": "Sara",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Rebekkah",
      "Rachel"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1475,
    "question": "After Jesus fed the 5,000 how many baskets were left over?",
    "answer": "12",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "10",
      "7"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1744,
    "question": "When Christians observe Palm Sunday, what are they celebrating?",
    "answer": "Jesus’ entry into Jerusalem",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The Passover",
      "The Feast of Tabernacles"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1854,
    "question": "Who said, Lord, if it be thou, bid me come unto thee on the water?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Thomas"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 14:28"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which woman became queen and saved her people?",
    "answer": "Esther",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Vashti",
      "Rahab"
    ],
    "reference": "Esther 4:14"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Who was the left-handed judge who killed King Eglon?",
    "answer": "Ehud",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Samson",
      "Deborah"
    ],
    "reference": "Judges 3:15-21"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "What prophet saw a vision of a valley of dry bones?",
    "answer": "Ezekiel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jeremiah",
      "Daniel"
    ],
    "reference": "Ezekiel 37:1-10"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Who was the prophet taken to heaven in a whirlwind?",
    "answer": "Elijah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Elisha",
      "Enoch"
    ],
    "reference": "2 Kings 2:11"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Which apostle survived a snake bite on Malta?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Barnabas",
      "Timothy"
    ],
    "reference": "Acts 28:3-6"
  },
  {
    "id": 501,
    "question": "Who did Jesus talk to about the wind blowing where it wants?",
    "answer": "Nicodemus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Joseph of Arimathea",
      "Gamaliel"
    ],
    "reference": "John 3:4-8"
  },
  {
    "id": 502,
    "question": "According to 2 Timothy 3:16 all Scripture is:",
    "answer": "God-breathed and useful for his purposes",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Written by human wisdom and tradition",
      "Only the words of the prophets and apostles"
    ],
    "reference": "2 Timothy 3:16"
  },
  {
    "id": 503,
    "question": "According to Jesus what is one of the most important commandments in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Love God with all your heart",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Do not eat certain foods",
      "Give offerings in public so others can see"
    ],
    "reference": "Mark 12:29-31"
  },
  {
    "id": 504,
    "question": "In 1 Corinthians, what is the greatest of the imperishable qualities?",
    "answer": "Love",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Faith",
      "Hope"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 506,
    "question": "According to the Gospel of Matthew, where does Jesus give his first public sermon?",
    "answer": "On the mount",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Bethany",
      "Jereusalem"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 508,
    "question": "What is the shortest verse in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Jesus Wept",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "God is love",
      "In the beginning"
    ],
    "reference": "John 11:35"
  },
  {
    "id": 514,
    "question": "How was Moses saved from Pharaoh's murderous decree?",
    "answer": "He was put in a basket",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hid in a cave",
      "Ravens fed him"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 515,
    "question": "David protected his flock from two dangerous animals Which ones?",
    "answer": "bear and lion",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "wold and tiger",
      "leopard and hyena"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Samuel 17:34-37"
  },
  {
    "id": 516,
    "question": "Who helped Jacob steal the birthright from his older brother?",
    "answer": "Rebekah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Rachel",
      "Leah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 517,
    "question": "At what age did Jesus begin his ministry?",
    "answer": "Around 30 years old",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Around 21 years old",
      "Around 40 years old"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 3:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 519,
    "question": "What was Paul of Tarsus's original name?",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Simon",
      "Samuel"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 520,
    "question": "Who carried the children of Israel captive into Assyria?",
    "answer": "Tiglathpileser",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nebuchadnezzar",
      "Pharoah"
    ],
    "reference": "2 Kgs 15:29"
  },
  {
    "id": 522,
    "question": "God loves the world so much that he did what?",
    "answer": "Gave his son",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sent a great flood",
      "Gave the Ten Commandments"
    ],
    "reference": "John 3:16"
  },
  {
    "id": 523,
    "question": "Complete this verse from Job: \"\"for the price of wisdom is …………",
    "answer": "above rubies",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "greater than gold",
      "more precious than silver"
    ],
    "reference": "Job 28:18"
  },
  {
    "id": 525,
    "question": "Concerning which disciple did the rumor spread that he would not die?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Luke",
      "Mark"
    ],
    "reference": "John 21:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 526,
    "question": "How long did Paul minister in the school of Tyrannus at Ephesus?",
    "answer": "2 Years",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "3 Years",
      "12 Years"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 530,
    "question": "Finish this verse “In every battle you will need faith as your ______ to stop the fiery arrows aimed at you by Satan”",
    "answer": "Shield",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sword",
      "Helmet"
    ],
    "reference": "Ephesians 6:16"
  },
  {
    "id": 534,
    "question": "Where did Paul's conversion take place?",
    "answer": "Road to Damascus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Road to Emmaus",
      "Mount Sinai"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 535,
    "question": "What was Esau's occupation?",
    "answer": "Hunter",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Farmer",
      "Carpenter"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 536,
    "question": "How did Esau respond when his birthright was taken?",
    "answer": "Threatened to kill Jacob",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Forgave Jacob immediately",
      "Left home and never returned"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 537,
    "question": "How did God appear to Moses in the book of Exodus?",
    "answer": "Through a burning bush",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "As a dove descending from heaven",
      "Through a talking donkey"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 539,
    "question": "How did God make humanity spread out across the earth?",
    "answer": "Confused their languages",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Divided the continents",
      "Sent them out two by two"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 540,
    "question": "How did Jesus reveal the one who would betray him?",
    "answer": "Shared a piece of bread",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Pointed to him",
      "Wrote his name in the sand"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 541,
    "question": "How did Joseph interpret Pharaoh’s dream?",
    "answer": "7 good years and 7 bad years",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "7 kingdoms rising and 7 falling",
      "7 days of rain and 7 days of sun"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 543,
    "question": "How did Judas identify Jesus to the soldiers?",
    "answer": "By kissing him",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "By pointing at him",
      "By calling out his name"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 545,
    "question": "How did Paul escape Damascus when the Jews were trying to kill him?",
    "answer": "In a basket over the city walls",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Disguised himself as a soldier",
      "Fled through a secret tunnel"
    ],
    "reference": "Acts 9:25"
  },
  {
    "id": 549,
    "question": "How does the author of 1 John often refer to his readers?",
    "answer": "Children",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Servants",
      "Brothers"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 551,
    "question": "How long did Moses’s mother hide him to escape the death edict of Pharaoh?",
    "answer": "3 months",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "4 months",
      "2 months"
    ],
    "reference": "Exod 2:2"
  },
  {
    "id": 552,
    "question": "How long did the children of Israel journey in the wilderness of Shur before they found water?",
    "answer": "3 days",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "7 days",
      "13 days"
    ],
    "reference": "Exod 15:22"
  },
  {
    "id": 557,
    "question": "How long were the children of Israel in Egypt?",
    "answer": "215 years",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "100 years",
      "70 years"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 561,
    "question": "What's the second last book in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Jude",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "2 John",
      "3 John"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 564,
    "question": "How many brothers did Joseph have?",
    "answer": "11",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "10",
      "12"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 565,
    "question": "How many chapters are there in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "929",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "836",
      "1022"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 566,
    "question": "How many close disciples did Jesus have?",
    "answer": "12",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "10",
      "7"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 6:12-16"
  },
  {
    "id": 571,
    "question": "How many days did Lazarus remain in the tomb before Jesus raised him?",
    "answer": "4 days",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "7 days",
      "3 days"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 572,
    "question": "How many human couples entered Noah's ark?",
    "answer": "4",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "8",
      "2"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 7:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 580,
    "question": "How many wonders did Elijah and Elisha perform altogether?",
    "answer": "24",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "19",
      "29"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 582,
    "question": "How much did Judas betray Jesus for?",
    "answer": "30 silver coins",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "20 silver coins",
      "50 silver coins"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 583,
    "question": "How old was Abraham when Isaac was born?",
    "answer": "100",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "90",
      "120"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 586,
    "question": "How old was Joseph when his brethren sold him into slavery?",
    "answer": "17",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "16",
      "18"
    ],
    "reference": "Gen 37:2"
  },
  {
    "id": 589,
    "question": "How were the children of Israel guided in their forty years of wandering in the wilderness?",
    "answer": "By a pillar of cloud",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "By a star in the sky",
      "By a voice in the clouds"
    ],
    "reference": "Exod 13:21"
  },
  {
    "id": 591,
    "question": "In the Acts of the Apostles who is Stephen?",
    "answer": "The first Christian martyr",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The first disciple",
      "The first apostle"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 592,
    "question": "In the book of Philemon who is Paul's fellow prisoner?",
    "answer": "Epaphras",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Timothy",
      "Barnabas"
    ],
    "reference": "Philemon 1:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 593,
    "question": "Which disciple doubts Jesus’s resurrection until he sees him with his own eyes?",
    "answer": "Thomas",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Philip",
      "Peter"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 594,
    "question": "In the Gospel of Mark, how does Mary learn of her pregnancy?",
    "answer": "From the angel Gabriel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Joseph sees it in a dream",
      "Martha tells her"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 600,
    "question": "In which book of the bible do we read about Haman?",
    "answer": "Esther",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Ruth",
      "Deborah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 601,
    "question": "In which books of the Bible is the story of Jesus' birth told?",
    "answer": "Matthew and Luke",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Romans and Acts",
      "John and Mark"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 1 and 2; Luke 2"
  },
  {
    "id": 605,
    "question": "Jacob sent Joseph to his brothers, where did he find them?",
    "answer": "Dothan",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Bethany"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 606,
    "question": "James used the example of which Old Testament figure to demonstrate how the prayers of a righteous man can have powerful results?",
    "answer": "Elijah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Elisha",
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "reference": "James 5:13-18"
  },
  {
    "id": 609,
    "question": "Judas Iscariot betrayed Jesus for thirty pieces of silver What was thirty pieces of silver equivalent to?",
    "answer": "The price of a slave",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The price of a sacrificial lamb",
      "The price of a field of land"
    ],
    "reference": "Exodus 21:32"
  },
  {
    "id": 612,
    "question": "Name a king who disguised themselves before going into battle and was slain by archers",
    "answer": "Ahab",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Joash"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Kings 22:34; 2 Chron 35:22"
  },
  {
    "id": 614,
    "question": "Of what wood was Noah’s Ark made?",
    "answer": "Gopher",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sycamore",
      "Cedar"
    ],
    "reference": "Gen 6:14"
  },
  {
    "id": 616,
    "question": "Which city were Paul and Silas imprisoned in during the second missionary journey?",
    "answer": "Philippi",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Corinth",
      "Jerusalem"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 617,
    "question": "Paul says Christians should follow whose example?",
    "answer": "Christ’s example",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Elijah's example",
      "Moses' example"
    ],
    "reference": "Ephesians 5"
  },
  {
    "id": 618,
    "question": "Paul was shipwrecked on what island?",
    "answer": "Malta",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Patmos",
      "Cicily"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 620,
    "question": "Before raising Eutychus from the dead, Paul preached a long sermon. What time did it end?",
    "answer": "Midnight",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sunrise",
      "Sunset"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 621,
    "question": "The Bible is divided into how many testaments?",
    "answer": "2",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "3",
      "1"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 624,
    "question": "To what city was Saul traveling when he encountered a great and blinding light?",
    "answer": "Damascus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Bethany"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 625,
    "question": "Upon what mountain was Israel cursed for disobedience?",
    "answer": "Mount Ebal",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Mount Sinai",
      "Mount Hebron"
    ],
    "reference": "Deut 27:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 627,
    "question": "What \"\"ran violently down a steep place into the sea and perished in the waters\"\"?",
    "answer": "A herd of swine",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A flock of sheep",
      "A flock of gaots"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 8:32"
  },
  {
    "id": 630,
    "question": "What are the names of Joseph’s two sons?",
    "answer": "Ephraim and Manasseh",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Benjamin and Judah",
      "Reuben and Simeon"
    ],
    "reference": "Gen 41:51–52"
  },
  {
    "id": 631,
    "question": "What Athenian judge was converted under Paul’s preaching?",
    "answer": "Dionysius",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Damaris",
      "Crispus"
    ],
    "reference": "Acts 17:34"
  },
  {
    "id": 634,
    "question": "What did a woman do to Jesus in the house of Simon the leper at Bethany?",
    "answer": "Anoint him with oil",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Prepared a meal for him",
      "Sat at his feet and heard his words"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 26:6-7"
  },
  {
    "id": 635,
    "question": "What did Esau receive in exchange for his birthright?",
    "answer": "Some stew",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A lamb",
      "The firstfruits"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 636,
    "question": "What did God ask Abraham to sacrifice on Mount Moriah?",
    "answer": "His only son",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Seven yearling lambs",
      "His only daughter"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 639,
    "question": "What did God tell Abraham to look at when he made him a promise?",
    "answer": "The stars in the sky",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The mountains",
      "The sand on the sea"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 641,
    "question": "What did Herod and Pilate become when Jesus stood on trial before them?",
    "answer": "Friends",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Enemies",
      "Betrayers"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 23:12"
  },
  {
    "id": 642,
    "question": "What did Jacob do most of the time?",
    "answer": "Stayed at home with his mother",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hunted in the woods",
      "Traveled to distant lands"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 643,
    "question": "What did Jesus do before feeding the 5,000",
    "answer": "Pray to give thanks",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sent them to find food",
      "Taught them to fish"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 647,
    "question": "What did Joshua command to stay still?",
    "answer": "Moon & Sun",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The Egyptian armies",
      "The Amalekite armies"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 648,
    "question": "What did Laban make Jacob do to finally marry Rachel?",
    "answer": "Work another seven years",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Work another fourteen years",
      "Offer his firstborn in service"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 650,
    "question": "What did Saul encounter when he was traveling to Damascus?",
    "answer": "A great and blinding light",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Two travelers telling him of Jesus",
      "Jesus walking toward him"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 655,
    "question": "What does Jahwe-Schammah mean?",
    "answer": "God is there",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The Lord will provide",
      "God our healer"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 656,
    "question": "What does Paul call the Galatians?",
    "answer": "foolish",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "wise",
      "afraid"
    ],
    "reference": "Galatians 3:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 658,
    "question": "What does Paul say may “abound more and more in knowledge and in all judgment?”",
    "answer": "Love",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Faith",
      "Hope"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 667,
    "question": "What happened to Galileans while offering sacrifices?",
    "answer": "They were slaughtered",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "They were given help",
      "They were arrested"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 13:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 668,
    "question": "What is the central theme of the Bible?",
    "answer": "Jesus Christ",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Judgement",
      "Righteousness"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 676,
    "question": "What is the longest chapter in the bible?",
    "answer": "Psalm 119",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Psalm 117",
      "Psalm 118"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 677,
    "question": "What is the longest verse in the bible?",
    "answer": "Esther 8:9",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Ezra 7:11",
      "1 Kings 8:1"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 678,
    "question": "What is the name of the oldest person mentioned in the Bible?",
    "answer": "Methuselah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Enoch",
      "Noah"
    ],
    "reference": "lived 969 years"
  },
  {
    "id": 679,
    "question": "What is the name of the disciple who betrayed Jesus?",
    "answer": "Judas",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "John"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 26:14-16"
  },
  {
    "id": 680,
    "question": "What is the name of the island where John wrote the book of Revelation?",
    "answer": "Patmos",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Malta",
      "Cyprus"
    ],
    "reference": "Revelation 1:9"
  },
  {
    "id": 681,
    "question": "What is the name of the sea where Jesus calmed the storm?",
    "answer": "Sea of Galilee",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Dead Sea",
      "Mediterranean Sea"
    ],
    "reference": "Mark 4:35-41"
  },
  {
    "id": 683,
    "question": "What is the name of the village where Christ turned water into wine?",
    "answer": "Cana",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Dothan",
      "Corinth"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 684,
    "question": "What is the original meaning of the word 'Bible'?",
    "answer": "Books",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Answers",
      "Love"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 687,
    "question": "What is the shortest book in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "3 John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "2 John",
      "Jude"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 688,
    "question": "What is the shortest chapter in the bible?",
    "answer": "Psalm 117",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Psalm 105",
      "Psalm 129"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 691,
    "question": "What king of Judah had his eyes put out?",
    "answer": "Zedekiah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hezekiah",
      "Saul"
    ],
    "reference": "2 Kings 25:7"
  },
  {
    "id": 692,
    "question": "What king was guilty of idolatry in making two golden calves",
    "answer": "Jeroboam",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Solomon",
      "Rehoboam"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Kgs 12:28"
  },
  {
    "id": 693,
    "question": "What king was killed by his own sons?",
    "answer": "Sennacherib",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Rehoboam",
      "Zedekiah"
    ],
    "reference": "2 Kgs 19:36"
  },
  {
    "id": 695,
    "question": "What names was Moses supposed to give to the Israelites when asked about who had sent him?",
    "answer": "I am who I am",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "God our salvation",
      "I am the one who listens"
    ],
    "reference": "Exodus 3:13-14"
  },
  {
    "id": 696,
    "question": "What occupation did Paul of Tarsus follow?",
    "answer": "Tent maker",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Carpenter",
      "Tax collector"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 697,
    "question": "What Pharisee gave a feast that Jesus attended?",
    "answer": "Simon",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "John"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 7:36-50"
  },
  {
    "id": 702,
    "question": "What tribe is Paul from?",
    "answer": "Benjamin",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Joseph",
      "Reuben"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 708,
    "question": "What was David’s occupation before he became king?",
    "answer": "Shepherd",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Carpenter",
      "Farmer"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 709,
    "question": "What was God’s original name for Abraham?",
    "answer": "Abram",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Terah",
      "Isaac"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 714,
    "question": "What was Isaiah’s father called?",
    "answer": "Amoz",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hezekiah",
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 719,
    "question": "What was Joseph’s brothers’ plan to do with him?",
    "answer": "Throw him in a pit to kill him",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Send him back to his father",
      "Welcome him into their arms"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 720,
    "question": "What was most likely the first Gospel written?",
    "answer": "Mark",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 721,
    "question": "What was most likely the first of Paul’s letters written?",
    "answer": "1 Thessalonians",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hebrews",
      "Galatians"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 722,
    "question": "What was most likely the last Gospel written?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Luke",
      "Mark"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 723,
    "question": "What was most likely the last New Testament book written?",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jude",
      "Acts"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 725,
    "question": "What was Peter's job before he became an apostle?",
    "answer": "Fisherman",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Tax collector",
      "Carpenter"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 727,
    "question": "What was Sarah’s idea for Abram to have a child?",
    "answer": "Have a child with Hagar",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Wait on God's faithfulness",
      "Animal sacrifice to appease God's wrath"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 729,
    "question": "What was Saul’s punishment for disobeying God?",
    "answer": "Kingdom torn away",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Kingdom given to his son",
      "Kingdom sold into slavery"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 731,
    "question": "What was Solomon famous for?",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Power",
      "Riches"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 732,
    "question": "What was the tabernacle for?",
    "answer": "A sanctuary for worship",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A refuge for sinners",
      "A fortified tower for defense"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 733,
    "question": "What was the eighth plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Locusts",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Darkness",
      "Water turned to blood"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 737,
    "question": "What was the height of Goliath?",
    "answer": "Six cubits and a span",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Five cubits",
      "Seven cubits"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Sam 17:4"
  },
  {
    "id": 738,
    "question": "What was the judgment seat of Pilate known as?",
    "answer": "The Stone Pavement",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The Resting Place",
      "The Oathkeeper"
    ],
    "reference": "John 19:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 739,
    "question": "What was the name of Aaron’s (Moses’s brother) wife?",
    "answer": "Elisheba",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Zipporah",
      "Deborah"
    ],
    "reference": "Exod 6:23"
  },
  {
    "id": 740,
    "question": "What was the name of Abraham’s nephew?",
    "answer": "Lot",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Isaac",
      "Ishmael"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 742,
    "question": "What was the name of David’s father?",
    "answer": "Jesse",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Saul",
      "Jonathan"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 743,
    "question": "What was the name of Jacob’s daughter?",
    "answer": "Dinah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Rebekkah",
      "Sarah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 747,
    "question": "What was the name of the city founded by Cain after he left God's presence?",
    "answer": "Enoch",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Babel",
      "Ziklag"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 4:16-17"
  },
  {
    "id": 749,
    "question": "What was the name of the garden planted by God for the first couple?",
    "answer": "Garden of Eden",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Garden of Gethsemane",
      "The Hanging Gardens"
    ],
    "reference": "Genesis 2:8"
  },
  {
    "id": 750,
    "question": "What was the name of the high priest's servant whose ear was cut off by Simon Peter?",
    "answer": "Malchus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nicodemus",
      "Caiaphas"
    ],
    "reference": "John 18:10"
  },
  {
    "id": 752,
    "question": "What was the name of the man who asked Pilate for Jesus' body?",
    "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nicodemus",
      "Simon of Cyrene"
    ],
    "reference": "John 19:38-42"
  },
  {
    "id": 755,
    "question": "What was the name of the Roman governor who heard Paul?",
    "answer": "Felix",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Festus",
      "Pilate"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 756,
    "question": "What was the name of the woman who anointed Jesus' feet?",
    "answer": "Mary",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Martha",
      "Elizabeth"
    ],
    "reference": "John 12:1-8"
  },
  {
    "id": 757,
    "question": "What was the name of the woman who hid the spies at Jericho?",
    "answer": "Rahab",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Ruth",
      "Sarah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 758,
    "question": "What was the ninth plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Water turned to blood",
      "Locusts"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 759,
    "question": "What was the other name of Tabitha a woman who was raised from the dead?",
    "answer": "Dorcas",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Lydia",
      "Priscilla"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 763,
    "question": "What was the seventh plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Hail",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Locusts",
      "Death of first-born"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 764,
    "question": "What was the tenth plague on Egypt?",
    "answer": "Death of first-born",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hail",
      "Locusts"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 765,
    "question": "What was the total number of the children of Israel that went down to Egypt?",
    "answer": "70",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "60",
      "80"
    ],
    "reference": "Gen 46:27"
  },
  {
    "id": 768,
    "question": "What were men trying to do at the Tower of Babel?",
    "answer": "Reach heaven",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Stop the weather",
      "Worship idols"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 769,
    "question": "What was another name for Solomon?",
    "answer": "Jedediah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jeroboam",
      "Rehoboam"
    ],
    "reference": "2 Sam 12:25; Prov 31:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 770,
    "question": "What were the “Urim and Thummim”?",
    "answer": "Lots",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sacred scrolls",
      "The ten commandments"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 773,
    "question": "What’s the first line of the Lord’s Prayer?",
    "answer": "Our Father which art in heaven",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hallowed by thy name",
      "Thy kingdom come"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 775,
    "question": "What’s the last word in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Curse",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Love",
      "Hope"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 778,
    "question": "What’s the shortest book in the Old Testament?",
    "answer": "Obadiah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Amos",
      "Joel"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 780,
    "question": "When God showed Abram the stars in the sky, what did he promise?",
    "answer": "More descendants than the number of stars",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Land as far as the eye could see",
      "Conquest of his enemies"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 781,
    "question": "When Jacob met Laban, which daughter did he want to marry?",
    "answer": "Rachel",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Sarah",
      "Rebekkah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 782,
    "question": "When Jesus descended from the mount of transfiguration he was greeted by:",
    "answer": "A man who sought healing for his epileptic son",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "A blind man",
      "A leper"
    ],
    "reference": "Mark 9:1-18"
  },
  {
    "id": 783,
    "question": "When Rachel left home with Jacob her husband what did she steal from her father Laban?",
    "answer": "Laban’s household gods",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "All Laban's sheep",
      "Laban's servants"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 784,
    "question": "When Saul was pursuing David in which cave did David seek refuge?",
    "answer": "Cave of Adullam",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Cave of En-Gedi",
      "Cave of Machpelah"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Sam 22:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 787,
    "question": "Where did God send Moses to deliver the children of Israel out of Egypt?",
    "answer": "Pharaoh",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Into the wilderness",
      "Through the red sea"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 788,
    "question": "Where did Hagar and her son leave to?",
    "answer": "Into the desert",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Into Egypt",
      "Into Canaan"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 791,
    "question": "Where did Mary bring her newborn son Jesus \"\"when the days of her purification according to the law of Moses were accomplished\"\"?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Bethlehem",
      "Nazareth"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 2:22"
  },
  {
    "id": 793,
    "question": "Where did Paul see a vision of Jesus?",
    "answer": "Road to Damascus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Road to Emmaus",
      "Red Sea"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 795,
    "question": "Where was an altar erected “to the unknown God”?",
    "answer": "Athens",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Corinth",
      "Rome"
    ],
    "reference": "Acts 17:22–23"
  },
  {
    "id": 797,
    "question": "Where was Jesus crucified?",
    "answer": "Golgotha",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Ephesus"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 799,
    "question": "Where was Moses buried?",
    "answer": "In the valley of Moab",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "In the red sea",
      "In the valley of dry bones"
    ],
    "reference": "Deut 34:6"
  },
  {
    "id": 800,
    "question": "Where was Paul stoned?",
    "answer": "Lystra",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Corinth",
      "Galatia"
    ],
    "reference": "Acts 14:19"
  },
  {
    "id": 801,
    "question": "Where were the disciples first called “Christians”?",
    "answer": "Antioch",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Corinth",
      "Rome"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 802,
    "question": "Which animal spoke to Balaam?",
    "answer": "Donkey",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Serpent",
      "Raven"
    ],
    "reference": "Numbers 22:28"
  },
  {
    "id": 803,
    "question": "Which apostle led a blind man out of the city to heal him?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Barnabas",
      "Peter"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 807,
    "question": "Which biblical narrative is connected to Palm Sunday?",
    "answer": "Jesus’ entry into Jerusalem",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jesus' resurrection",
      "Jesus' death on the cross"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 815,
    "question": "Which Gospel is most concerned with the mystery and identity of the person of Jesus?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Luke",
      "Mark"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 816,
    "question": "Which Gospel is written by a doctor?",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Mark",
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 818,
    "question": "Which gospel records the fewest of the miracles performed by Jesus?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 820,
    "question": "Which human author wrote the most books?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Mark"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 825,
    "question": "Which literary genre does Jesus implement to help preach his message?",
    "answer": "Parables",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Epistles",
      "Poetry"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 827,
    "question": "Which New Testament book has Jesus’ Sermon on the Mount?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Luke",
      "John"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 829,
    "question": "Which of the disciples denied Jesus?",
    "answer": "Peter",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "John",
      "Thomas"
    ],
    "reference": "Mark 14:66-72"
  },
  {
    "id": 835,
    "question": "Which prophet is known for turning his rod into a bronze snake?",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Aaron",
      "Elijah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 836,
    "question": "Which Roman was in charge of cultivation in Syria at the time of Jesus’ birth?",
    "answer": "Quirinus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Augustus",
      "Tiberius"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 839,
    "question": "Which book start with \"\"In the beginning\"\"?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Revelation",
      "Malichi"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 840,
    "question": "Name an Old Testament character who appeared with Jesus at the transfiguration?",
    "answer": "Elijah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Elisha",
      "Enoch"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 845,
    "question": "Who asked Jesus if they could be permitted to call down fire from heaven upon the Samaritans?",
    "answer": "James",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "Judas"
    ],
    "reference": "Luke 9:52-54"
  },
  {
    "id": 851,
    "question": "Who climbed a mountain at 120 years old and never came back?",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Aaron",
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 854,
    "question": "Who did Abraham send to find Isaac a wife?",
    "answer": "His oldest servant",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "His brother",
      "His wife"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 857,
    "question": "Who did Isaac favor of his two sons?",
    "answer": "Esau",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Jacob",
      "Ishmael"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 859,
    "question": "Who did Laban trick Jacob into marrying?",
    "answer": "Leah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Rebekkah",
      "Keturah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 860,
    "question": "Who did Moses drown by closing the Red Sea?",
    "answer": "The Egyptians",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The Amalekites",
      "The Hittites"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 876,
    "question": "Who murders John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Herod Antipas",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Herod Agrippa",
      "Herod the Great"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 877,
    "question": "Who pretended to be mad to avoid capture and death at the hands of an enemy king?",
    "answer": "David",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Saul",
      "Jonathan"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Samuel 21:13"
  },
  {
    "id": 882,
    "question": "Who requested for the head of John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Herodias",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Herod Antipas",
      "Caiphas"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 883,
    "question": "Who restored Paul’s sight after the Lord blinded him?",
    "answer": "Ananias",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Timothy",
      "Peter"
    ],
    "reference": "Acts 9:17–18"
  },
  {
    "id": 884,
    "question": "Who rolled the stone closing Jesus' tomb?",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Nicodemus",
      "Judas"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 27:59-60"
  },
  {
    "id": 890,
    "question": "Who said: „Greater love hath no man than this that a man lay down his life for his friends“?",
    "answer": "Jesus",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Paul",
      "John the Baptist"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 893,
    "question": "Who said: „The LORD gave and the LORD hath taken away; blessed be the name of the LORD“?",
    "answer": "Job",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Moses",
      "Hannah"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 894,
    "question": "Who suggested that Joseph interpret the dreams of Pharaoh?",
    "answer": "The cupbearer",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "His brothers",
      "His father"
    ],
    "reference": "Gen 41:12–13"
  },
  {
    "id": 896,
    "question": "Who wanted to kill Jesus when he was a baby?",
    "answer": "Herod",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Pharoah",
      "The wisemen"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 903,
    "question": "Who was David’s captain?",
    "answer": "Joab",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Abner",
      "Josheb"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 904,
    "question": "Who was David’s son that started a rebellion against him?",
    "answer": "Absalom",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Solomon",
      "Reheboam"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 906,
    "question": "Who was Moses’s father-in-law?",
    "answer": "Jethro",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Amram",
      "Aaron"
    ],
    "reference": "Exod 3:1"
  },
  {
    "id": 907,
    "question": "Who was Solomon’s mother?",
    "answer": "Bathsheba",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Abigail",
      "Rahab"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 908,
    "question": "Who was the chief of the three mighty men of David?",
    "answer": "Josheb-basshebeth",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Eleazar",
      "Shammah"
    ],
    "reference": "2 Sam 23:8"
  },
  {
    "id": 910,
    "question": "Who was the father of John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Zechariah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Malachi",
      "Amos"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 912,
    "question": "Who was the first born son of David?",
    "answer": "Amnon",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Solomon",
      "Reheboam"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 913,
    "question": "Who was the first king of Israel?",
    "answer": "Saul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Solmon"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 916,
    "question": "Who was the first person to come upon the injured man in the parable of the Good Samaritan?",
    "answer": "Priest",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "The Levite",
      "The Good Samaritan"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 920,
    "question": "Who was the grandson of Samuel?",
    "answer": "Heman",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Joel",
      "Abijah"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Chronicles 6:33"
  },
  {
    "id": 921,
    "question": "Who was the Hebrew judge that Delilah seduced to hand over to the Philistine army?",
    "answer": "Samson",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Gideon",
      "Ehud"
    ],
    "reference": "Judges 16:18-20"
  },
  {
    "id": 922,
    "question": "Who was the high priest during the time of Zechariah?",
    "answer": "Joshua",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Ezra",
      "Jehoiada"
    ],
    "reference": "Zech 6:10-11"
  },
  {
    "id": 925,
    "question": "Who was the last king of Israel?",
    "answer": "Hoshea",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Zedekiah",
      "Joash"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 927,
    "question": "Who was the most wicked king of Israel?",
    "answer": "Ahab",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Joash",
      "Hezekiah"
    ],
    "reference": "1 Kgs 21:25"
  },
  {
    "id": 928,
    "question": "Who was the mother of John the Baptist?",
    "answer": "Elizabeth",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hannah",
      "Martha"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 930,
    "question": "Who was the mother of Samuel?",
    "answer": "Hannah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Zipporah",
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 931,
    "question": "Who was the priest of Bethel during the time of Amos?",
    "answer": "Amaziah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Joshua",
      "Azariah"
    ],
    "reference": "Amos 7:10"
  },
  {
    "id": 937,
    "question": "Who went with Paul on his first missionary journey?",
    "answer": "Barnabas",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Timothy",
      "Silas"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 939,
    "question": "Who was a sibling of Moses??",
    "answer": "Miriam",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Joshua",
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "reference": "Exodus 15:20-21 and Exodus 6:16-20"
  },
  {
    "id": 941,
    "question": "Who was the father of king Josiah?",
    "answer": "Jedidah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Hezekiah",
      "Joash"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 942,
    "question": "Who worked as a tax collector before preaching the word of God?",
    "answer": "Matthew",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Judas",
      "Peter"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 943,
    "question": "Who would have nothing to do with the author of 3 John?",
    "answer": "Diotrephes",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Gaius",
      "Demetrius"
    ],
    "reference": "3 John 1:9"
  },
  {
    "id": 944,
    "question": "Who wrote most of the books in the New Testament?",
    "answer": "Paul",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Mark",
      "Jesus"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 945,
    "question": "Who wrote the Acts of the Apostles?",
    "answer": "Luke",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Paul",
      "John"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 946,
    "question": "Who wrote the Book of Revelation?",
    "answer": "John",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Paul",
      "Mark"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 950,
    "question": "Why did God send the ten plagues?",
    "answer": "Pharaoh refused to let the Israelites free",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "To distract the Amalekites",
      "To defeat the Philistines"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1481,
    "question": "As Isaac was dying and blind, who suggested that Jacob should steal the blessing?",
    "answer": "Rebekah",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Esau",
      "Abraham"
    ],
    "reference": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 1852,
    "question": "Who said I say to my servant, Go, and he goes?",
    "answer": "A Centurion",
    "wrongAnswers": [
      "Philippians",
      "Goliath"
    ],
    "reference": "Matthew 8:8"
  }
]
